{"tossups": [{"question": "The \"sha0\" type of this quantity is the amount of this quantity over and above its \"&amp;ow\" type. For a polytropic process with \"n equals one,\" (read slowly) \"P V natural log of V2 over V1\" is the \"boundary\" type of this quantity. In statics, the total virtual example of this quantity is zero if a system in equilibrium undergoes a virtual displacement. In thermodynamics, the magnitude of this quantity can be de ned as pressure integrated with respect to volume. Planck's constant times the frequency of incident light minus the value for a function denoted by this term is the maximum kinetic energy of an electron emitted from a metal in the photoelectric effect. For a conservative force acting on an object, it is equal to the negative of the change in potential energy. For 10 points, what quantity is de ned as the dot product of a force acting through a displacement or, more simply, as force times distance?", "answer": "work [accept sha0 work or &amp;ow work or work function]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>work</u></b> [accept <b><u>sha0 work</u></b> or <b><u>&amp</u></b>; ow work or work function]", "acceptable": ["work", "work", "sha0 work", "&amp"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "After Cu\u0301chulainn (koo-KULL-en) broke one of these objects belonging to Sca\u0301thach's (SKAH-tahk's) daughter Uathach (WAH-tahk), Cochar Croibhe (KOH-kar CROY-vuh) challenged him to a duel and was quickly killed by Cu\u0301chulainn's javelin. In the Mabinogion, Taliesin tricks Rhun into taking one of these body parts from a maid in order to prove the infidelity of Elphin's wife. Objects of this type belonging to the Inuit goddess Sedna became seals and whales when her father Anguta forced her off his boat. An epithet for the dawn goddess Eos describes these body parts as \"rosy.\" An Irish hero gained wisdom after burning one of these body parts while cooking the Salmon of Knowledge. In Greek mythology, these body parts name a race of smiths and magicians called the Dactyls. For 10 points, name these body parts, examples of which include Finn MacCool's thumb.", "answer": "fingers [accept specific fingers such as index finger; accept rosy-fingered; accept thumbs before \"thumb\"]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>fingers</u></b> [accept <b><u>specific fingers such as index finger</u></b>; accept <b><u>rosy-fingered</u></b>; accept <b><u>thumbs</u></b> before \"thumb]", "acceptable": ["fingers", "fingers", "specific fingers such as index finger", "rosy-fingered", "thumbs"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The writing of this text is depicted in the right panel of an altarpiece housed in a hospital in Bruges, in which its author looks at an inset circle showing a red-cloaked man. A painting once titled Profane Love was retitled for an event from this text and was cut down to a relatively square shape, removing an upper portion that may have depicted divine love. An entry in a set of 15 prints inspired by this text depicts two disembodied pillars that are positioned to look like the legs of a ray-encircled face that commands a man to eat a book. Various depictions of \"Death on a pale horse\" and El Greco's Opening of the Fifth Seal depict events from, for 10 points, what biblical book, which inspired Albrecht Du\u0308rer's engraving The Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse?", "answer": "Book of Revelation [prompt on \"Bible\" or \"New Testament\" before \"biblical\"; do not accept or prompt on \"(Book of) Revelations\"]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Book of Revelation</u></b> [prompt on <u>Bible</u> or <u>New Testament\"</u> before \"biblical; do not accept or prompt on \"(Book of) Revelations\"]", "acceptable": ["Book of Revelation", "Book of Revelation"], "promptable": ["Bible", "New Testament\""], "rejectable": ["(Book of) Revelations"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Welsh immigrants to this region founded a settlement called Y Wladfa (oh lad-vah). Early explorers of this region wrote sensationalized accounts of its native Tehuelche (tay-HWAIL-chay) people. A country's strategy of displacing this region's natives with European immigrants was called \"the conquest of the desert.\" A popular myth about this region originated in Antonio Pigafetta's account of traveling through it with the Magellan expedition. This region was said to be inhabited by a race of huge barbarians called its \"giants.\" This region to the south of Araucania (ah-rau-kah-NEE-ah) is an ancestral homeland of the Mapuche people and the southernmost region inhabited by \"gaucho\" cowboys. For 10 points, name this frontier region of far southern South America that includes Tierra del Fuego.", "answer": "Patagonia [accept Patagonian Giants; prompt on \"South America\" before \"desert\"]", "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Patagonia</u></b> [accept <b><u>Patagonian Giants</u></b>; prompt on <u>South America\"</u> before \"desert]", "acceptable": ["Patagonia", "Patagonia", "Patagonian Giants"], "promptable": ["South America\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in this profession imitates Barnes by smoking crack cocaine while trying to be \"Time's  rst human author of perfection.\" A man with this job named Casi (CAH-see) corresponds with the mentally disabled Jalen Kingg and is convinced by Dane to defraud the police and a drug kingpin in Sergio De La Pava's A Naked Singularity. Harry Lutz and Harold Basie are characters in this profession who spar over Oscar Crease's play Once at Antietam in William Gaddis's novel A Frolic of His Own, a satire of this profession. In a novel published in 2015, a pamphlet titled \"The Black Plague\" is found in the study of a man with this job who defends Zeebo, a son of Calpurnia. For 10 points, name this profession of Jean Louise's father Atticus in Harper Lee's Go Set a Watchman.", "answer": "awyers [or attorneys; or legal profession; accept public defenders or litigators]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>awyers</u></b> [or <b><u>attorneys</u></b>; or <b><u>legal profession</u></b>; accept <b><u>public defenders</u></b> or <b><u>litigators</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["awyers", "awyers", "attorneys", "legal profession", "public defenders", "litigators"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This protein has a PHP domain in prokaryotes joined to its normal \" nger,\" \"thumb,\" and \"palm\" domains. A reaction catalyzed by this enzyme is assayed by the delta\u00c2\u2013delta\u00c2\u2013C method. NEB markets the Q5 form of this protein, which is used in Gibson assemblies as a fusion protein called Phusion, with a \"P-H.\" Arthur Kornberg won a Nobel Prize for discovering this protein. PCNA clamps this enzyme to its substrate to enhance processivity. In the lab, this protein is mixed with magnesium chloride and d\u00c2\u00b7N\u00c2\u00b7T\u00c2\u00b7Ps and then thermally cycled between 72 degrees Celsius, 98 degrees Celsius, and the primer annealing temperature. Thermus aquaticus is the source of a heat-stable form of, for 10 points, what protein that elongates Okazaki fragments and ampli es DNA during a namesake \"chain reaction\"?", "answer": "DNA polymerase I [or DNA polymerase II; or any other number or Greek letter a0er it; or Taq polymerase; accept polymerase a0er \"DNA\"; prompt on \"polymerase\" before \"DNA\"]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>DNA polymerase I</u></b> [or <b><u>DNA polymerase II</u></b>; or <b><u>any other number</u></b> or <b><u>Greek letter a0er it</u></b>; or <b><u>Taq polymerase</u></b>; accept <b><u>polymerase a0er \"DNA</u></b>; prompt on <u>polymerase\"</u> before \"DNA]", "acceptable": ["DNA polymerase I", "DNA polymerase I", "DNA polymerase II", "any other number", "Greek letter a0er it", "Taq polymerase", "polymerase a0er \"DNA"], "promptable": ["polymerase\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "his country has implemented the \"Prevent\" strategy, which forces schools to report students who exhibit signs of terrorist activity. An alleged attempt by conservative Muslims to take over a public school system in this country was nicknamed \"Operation Trojan Horse.\" The hijab-wearing stand-up comic Shazia Mirza is from this country, where a political advertisement overlaid a photograph of Muslim refugees with the words \"Breaking Point.\" Before joining ISIS, \"Jihadi John\" lived in this country, where the Brazilian man Jean Charles de Menezes (meh-NEE-zis) was wrongly killed by police after a 2005 terror attack. In 2016, this country's capital city elected its  rst Muslim mayor, Sadiq Khan. For 10 points, in what country did fear over Muslim refugees partly motivate the Brexit campaign?", "answer": "United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland [accept either underlined portion; or U.K.; accept England]", "category": "Current Events", "subcategory": "Current Events", "answer_formatted": "United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern <b><u>Ireland</u></b> [accept <b><u>either underlined portion</u></b>; or <b><u>U.K.</u></b>; accept <b><u>England</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland", "Ireland", "either underlined portion", "U.K.", "England"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In Act II of the work this character appears in, he notices a buzzard &amp;ying over his hometown and sings for it to &amp;y away. He asks his partner to \"sing and dance for two instead of one\" in a duet with the refrain \"morning time and evening time and summertime and wintertime.\" Whenever this character is happy, a leitmotif reminiscent of his song \"I Got Plenty o' Nothing\" plays. The work this character appears in ends with him loading his goat cart and vowing to go to New York City. This character repeats the phrase \"you is\" in an aria that tells his lover \"you is my woman now.\" A DuBose Heyward novel and play are titled for this resident of Cat sh Row, who loses his lover to the drug dealer Sportin' Life. For 10 points, name this title character of a George Gershwin opera who loves Bess.", "answer": "Porgy", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Porgy</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Porgy", "Porgy"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The horns on a Pake (payk) doublet occur where this quantity is either parallel or perpendicular to the EFG tensor. In the lab frame, the tip angle is de ned with respect to this quantity, which, by convention, points along the z-axis. In continuous wave spectroscopy, this quantity is varied at constant frequency. Shimming homogenizes this vector quantity. Di\u00c2\u00b7polar broadening is minimized when the angle between it and a solid sample is 54.74 degrees, or the magic angle. The energy difference between two spin states is this quantity times the gyromagnetic ratio times h-bar. The local value for this quantity decreases in aromatic compounds, giving them high chemical shi0s since their protons are shielded. Nuclear spins precess about this vector in NMR. For 10 points, name this quantity measured in teslas.", "answer": "external magnetic  eld [or B; or H; or B-nought; or H-nought; prompt on  eld strength; prompt on external  eld strength]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>external magnetic  eld</u></b> [or <b><u>B</u></b>; or <b><u>H</u></b>; or <b><u>B-nought</u></b>; or <b><u>H-nought</u></b>; prompt on <u>eld strength</u>; prompt on <u>external  eld strength</u>]", "acceptable": ["external magnetic  eld", "external magnetic  eld", "B", "H", "B-nought", "H-nought"], "promptable": ["eld strength", "external  eld strength"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A man not known for writing in this language used it in a letter stating a desire to \"drill one hole after another\" into language until \"that which lurks behind\" begins \"seeping through.\" This language, which is not French, was used to write a play in which M, W1, and W2 appear in \"funeral urns.\" Eric Bentley translated into English a play written in this language that centers on a dispute following the insurrection of the \"Fat Prince,\" with the dispute being resolved when Azdak orders two women to pull a child. Samuel Beckett's Play was written in this language, which was used for a play in which Swiss Cheese dies during the Thirty Years' War. For 10 points, in what language were The Caucasian Chalk Circle and Mother Courage and Her Children written by Bertolt Brecht?", "answer": "German language [or Deutsch]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>German</u></b> language [or <b><u>Deutsch</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["German language", "German", "Deutsch"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Biblioteca Ambrosiana in Milan holds a lock of this woman's hair from which Lord Byron stole a single strand. Allegations of an affair involving this woman that may have produced the Infans Romanus led to her maid Pantiselia and the chamberlain Perotto Calderon being found dead in a river. Johann Burchard chronicled events in the life of this woman, who was widowed when Micheletto Corella assassinated her husband, a prince of Naples named Alfonso of Aragon. This daughter of Vannozza dei Cattanei (kah-tah-NAY-ee) feuded with Isabella d'Este while married to Alfonso I, Duke of Ferrara. She was rumored to own a hollow ring that she used to poison her enemies. Cesare (chuh-ZAH-ray) was the brother of, for 10 points, what woman whose father, Rodrigo, was better known as the scandalous Pope Alexander VI?", "answer": "Lucrezia Borgia [prompt on \"Borgia\"]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Lucrezia Borgia</u></b> [prompt on <u>Borgia</u>]", "acceptable": ["Lucrezia Borgia", "Lucrezia Borgia"], "promptable": ["Borgia"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One of these structures is sometimes depicted on the head of a syncretic form of Saraswati known as Benzaiten (ben-zye-ten). One of these structures sits atop a large rock that is \"married\" to a smaller rock by a large, elaborately knotted rope. Depending on the tradition, the beginning of a sando (sahn-doh) is marked by either a sanmon (sahn-mohn) or this similar but simpler structure. These structures, which are typically either unpainted or painted vermilion and black, may have evolved out of the tradition of hanging rice straw rope. They are named for \"sacred birds\" and typically consist of two pillars topped by an upper lintel and a lower tie beam. For 10 points, what structures, which provide a transition to the sacred environs of a Shinto temple, are traditional Japanese wooden gates?", "answer": "torii gates [prompt on \"gates\" before \"gates\"]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>torii</u></b> gates [prompt on <u>gates\"</u> before \"gates]", "acceptable": ["torii gates", "torii"], "promptable": ["gates\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In 1933, Daniel Katz and Kenneth Braly documented these constructs in \"one hundred college students\" who were asked to sort a list of 84 adjectives. Greg Walton and Geoffrey Cohen demonstrated the namesake \"li0\" or \"boost\" of these constructs in an experiment in which students were told information about other students. Joshua Aronson and Claude Steele conducted a study to see whether students would react to these constructs when taking a verbal GRE test that was described as either a diagnostic of intellectual ability or a laboratory study. A situation in which a person feels pressured to conform to these intergroup attitudes is known as their namesake \"threat.\" For 10 points, name these beliefs or thoughts about a particular group of individuals, which can be positive or negative.", "answer": "stereotypes [accept stereotype threat; accept more speci c answers mentioning stereotypes such as racial stereotypes or national stereotypes; do not accept or prompt on \"prejudice\" or other putative synonyms]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>stereotypes</u></b> [accept <b><u>stereotype threat</u></b>; accept <b><u>more speci c answers mentioning stereotypes such as racial stereotypes</u></b> or <b><u>national stereotypes</u></b>; do not accept or prompt on \"prejudice\" or \"other putative synonyms\"]", "acceptable": ["stereotypes", "stereotypes", "stereotype threat", "more speci c answers mentioning stereotypes such as racial stereotypes", "national stereotypes"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["prejudice", "other putative synonyms"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Lisel Mueller wrote that, among postwar Germans who did this activity, she was \"a Briar Rose, a Rip Van Winkle, / a stranger to the beginnings / they make from the stench of evil.\" W. H. Auden wrote that this activity only \"survives / in the valley of its making\" and \"makes nothing happen.\" In the same work, Auden wrote that \"Mad Ireland hurt\" the title person into doing this activity, allowing that man to \"teach the free man how to praise.\" A work titled for this activity claims that, if you demand both its raw material \"in all its rawness\" and that which is genuine, you are interested in this activity. Its performers are described as \"literalists of the imagination\" who create \"imaginary gardens with real toads in them.\" Marianne Moore wrote \"I too dislike it\" about, for 10 points, what type of writing?", "answer": "poetry [accept word forms such as writing poems; accept equivalents such as writing verse; prompt on \"writing\" or equivalents/word forms before \"titled\" and do not accept or prompt therea0er]", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>poetry</u></b> [accept <b><u>word forms such as writing poems</u></b>; accept <b><u>equivalents such as writing verse</u></b>; prompt on <u>writing</u> or <u>equivalents/word forms</u> before \"titled or <u>do not accept</u> or <u>prompt therea0er</u>]", "acceptable": ["poetry", "poetry", "word forms such as writing poems", "equivalents such as writing verse"], "promptable": ["writing", "equivalents/word forms", "do not accept", "prompt therea0er"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A ballet dedicated to this composer opens with a section titled \"Preghiera\" (preh-gee-\"AIR\"-ah) with music based on Franz Liszt's transcription of this composer's Ave verum corpus. Chopin wrote a set of variations based on one of this composer's works that inspired Robert Schumann to exclaim \"Hats off, gentlemen! A genius!\" This composer's third of  ve known violin concertos is in G major and is sometimes nicknamed for its \"Strasbourg\" theme. This composer of an A-major clarinet concerto for Anton Stadler wrote a sacred work with a second movement Kyrie (KEER-ee-ay) that contains a D-minor double fugue. He wrote only eight bars of that piece's Lacrimosa, which was  nished by Franz Su\u0308ssmayr. For 10 points, name this Austrian prodigy who composed 27 piano concertos and an un nished Requiem.", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart [or Johannes Chrysostomus Wolfgangus Theophilus Mozart]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Wolfgang Amadeus <b><u>Mozart</u></b> [or <b><u>Johannes Chrysostomus Wolfgangus Theophilus Mozart</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart", "Mozart", "Johannes Chrysostomus Wolfgangus Theophilus Mozart"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Overly dense regions in the primordial plasma are surrounded by spherical shells of acoustical oscillations denoted by this term that serve as standard rulers. Sphaleron transitions can convert a fraction of a number denoted capital L into a number named for this term. WMAP (w-\"map\") set as 0.024 the critical energy density described by this term times the square of the dimensionless Hubble parameter, small h. The abundance of elements due to big bang nucleosynthesis is determined using the eta parameter, the ratio of particles of this type to photons. Only about 4% of the universe's energy density is from matter made of particles of this type, whose creation is the subject of the Sakharov conditions. For 10 points, what type of particles contain three quarks and are exempli ed by protons and neutrons?", "answer": "baryonic [accept baryons or baryonic matter; prompt on \"normal (matter)\"]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>baryonic</u></b> [accept <b><u>baryons</u></b> or <b><u>baryonic matter</u></b>; prompt on <u>normal (matter)</u>]", "acceptable": ["baryonic", "baryonic", "baryons", "baryonic matter"], "promptable": ["normal (matter)"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An essay about this country anecdotally de nes its archetype of the \"Ultimate Peasant\" before describing how changes in this country's culture affected the essayist Richard Cobb. The careers of three singers from this country are detailed in the essay \"Spending Their Deaths on Holiday,\" which is included in a collection about this country's culture entitled Something to Declare. The word \"howcanaystinksotho\" (\"how can ay stink so though\") is Barbara Wright's attempt at translating the  rst word of a novel from this country. Gilbert Adair's translation of a novel from this country preserves its lipogram of avoiding the letter \"e.\" In a novel by Julian Barnes, Geoffrey Braithwaite travels this country in search of a certain author's stuffed parrot. For 10 points, name this home country of Raymond Queneau (kuh-noh), Georges Perec, and Gustave Flaubert.", "answer": "France [or French Republic; or Re\u0301publique franc\u0327aise]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>France</u></b> [or <b><u>French Republic</u></b>; or <b><u>Re\u0301publique franc\u0327aise</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["France", "France", "French Republic", "Re\u0301publique franc\u0327aise"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "At Ville-sur-Ancre (VEEL-soor-AHN-cur), Frederick Spring had Harry Farr executed for this offense, but modern-day historians believe that Farr may have been suffering from hyperacusis (\"hyper\"-ah-KYOO-sis). This offense titles a \"brief history\" written by Chris Walsh. Of the 346 men commemorated by the Shot at Dawn Memorial, 18 were executed for this offense, which was symbolized by white feathers. In 2006, the United Kingdom posthumously pardoned soldiers who were executed during World War I for desertion, forms of disobedience, and this offense. During the Sicily campaign of World War II, George Patton slapped soldiers hospitalized for shell shock because they were supposedly exhibiting the trait associated with this offense. For 10 points, name this failure to display courage in the face of the enemy.", "answer": "cowardice [accept word forms such as being cowards or cowardly; accept Cowardice: A Brief History; prompt on \"shell shock\" or \"refusing to  ght\" or equivalents]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>cowardice</u></b> [accept <b><u>word forms such as being cowards</u></b> or <b><u>cowardly</u></b>; accept <b><u>Cowardice: A Brief History</u></b>; prompt on <u>shell shock</u> or <u>refusing to  ght</u> or equivalents]", "acceptable": ["cowardice", "cowardice", "word forms such as being cowards", "cowardly", "Cowardice: A Brief History"], "promptable": ["shell shock", "refusing to  ght"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Fred Dretske (DRET-\"ski\") used the example of the possibility of a zebra being a cleverly disguised mule to illustrate his \"relative alternatives\" theory of this concept. Like Dretske, Saul Kripke (KRIP-\"key\") contended that this concept is not \"closed\" under a closure principle and critiqued another philosopher's reliabilist theory of this concept, which was put forth in the book Philosophical Explanations. The de nition of this concept is questioned in a scenario in which a job applicant believes that a man with ten coins in his pocket will get the job but doesn't realize that the man is himself. Robert Nozick developed a \"truth-tracking\" theory of this concept, which is the subject of \"Gettier problems\" that question Plato's de nition of it as \"justi ed true belief.\" For 10 points, name this concept studied in epistemology.", "answer": "knowledge [accept knowing or other answers mentioning forms of the word know]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>knowledge</u></b> [accept <b><u>knowing</u></b> or <b><u>other answers mentioning forms of the word know</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["knowledge", "knowledge", "knowing", "other answers mentioning forms of the word know"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The so-called \"Robin Hood\" of this river led an 1859 uprising that was put down by Captain \"Rip\" Ford's militia. Two states argued over the course of this river in the Country Club dispute. The Cortina disturbances occurred in this river's valley, which is also where Seth Thornton's patrol was ambushed. A regiment of buffalo soldiers stationed on this river allegedly killed a white bartender and were dishonorably discharged by Theodore Roosevelt. In the 1960s, a section of this river was forced into a concrete channel to resolve the Chamizal border dispute. A skirmish near this river inspired Abraham Lincoln's \"Spot Resolutions.\" Zachary Taylor's army marched to this river in order to provoke a war with Santa Anna's country. For 10 points, what river separates Texas from Mexico?", "answer": "Rio Grande [or Rio Bravo del Norte; do not accept or prompt on the \"Nueces River\"]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Rio Grande</u></b> [or <b><u>Rio Bravo del Norte</u></b>; do not accept or prompt on the \"\"Nueces River\"]", "acceptable": ["Rio Grande", "Rio Grande", "Rio Bravo del Norte"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["\"Nueces River"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A Norrish\u00c2\u2013Yang photoreaction forms a ring containing this many carbons. When UV light reacts with pyrimidines, it forms rings of this size. Ring D of taxol contains this many atoms. Counting the metal, the mechanism of a Ziegler\u00c2\u2013Natta catalyst forms a ring of this many atoms. The cyclo\u00c2\u00b7alkane of this size puckers between two \"butter&amp;y\" con gurations. Rings of this size are the smallest described by the Woodward\u00c2\u2013 Hoffmann rules. Tri\u00c2\u00b7phenyl\u00c2\u00b7phosphine oxide is formed by the rearrangement of a cyclic intermediate of this size in the Wittig reaction. The simplest antiaromatic hydrocarbon is a ring with this number of atoms. Beta-lactam antibiotics have a reactive central ring of this many atoms. Steroids have this many fused rings. For 10 points, give this number of carbons in cyclobutane.", "answer": "four", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>four</u></b>", "acceptable": ["four", "four"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}